冬祭  弗吉尼亞州 Ashburn
我想騎那匹有斑點的馬
I want to ride the spotty one.
好 一會再說吧
Well,we'll see.
- 你們餓了沒? - 你給我們買點吃的吧?
- Are you hungry? - Would you get us something?
來 我們去買吧 很快就回來
Come on,let's go. We'll be back.
- 他叫什麼名字? - 我不知道呢
- What's his name? - I don't know.
那我叫他小辣椒
I'd call him spicy.
- 那匹呢? - 小糖心?
- What about that one? - Sugar?
- 小糖心和辣椒? - 小辣椒兒
- Sugar and spice? - Spicy.
好撓喔
It's too scratchy.
癢 是好癢 所以你才要撓癢癢
Itchy. It's itchy. That's why you're scratching.
Lindsay! Lindsay! Lindsay! Lindsay!
有沒人看到我女兒啊?
Has anyone seen my daughter?
Lindsay! 幫幫我!
Lindsay! Help!
Aimee Aimee?
Aimee. Aimee?
Aimee! Aimee?
- 哦天啊 - Barbara 發生什麼事了?
- Oh my god. - Barbara,what's going on?
她剛剛還在這堛 她不見了
She was just right here. She's not here.
- 她去找你們了嗎? - 沒有 她去了哪?
- Did she come to you guys? - No. Where is she?
她剛剛還在這堛 Aimee! Aimee!
She was just right here. Aimee! Aimee!
什麼叫她不見了? 她走去哪堣F?
What do you mean,she's gone? Which way did she go?
- 我不知道! - Aimee!
- I don't know. - Aimee!
Lynch夫人? 我們是FBI
Mrs. Lynch? We're with the fbi.
這就是Aimee最近的照片麼?
Is this the most recent photo you have of aimee?
是的
Yes.
Aimee Lynch 8歲 一小時前 在Ashburn的冬祭活動上被拐走了
Aimee lynch,8 years old, Was taken an hour ago from a winter festival in ashburn.
有目擊者麼?
Any witnesses?
她不見的時候 她媽媽Barbara就在她身邊
Her mom barbara Was right next to her when she vanished.
那埵釵n幾百人 沒有人看見任何東西?
There must have been hundreds of people there. No one saw anything?
是個臨時聚會 幾乎沒有什麼保安工作的
It's a temporary gathering, With little to no security.
這樣吧 Reid 你跟我去他們家
All right,reid, You and I are going to head to the family's house.
你們倆 你們跟Garcia一起
The two of you, I want you to work with garcia.
查看去年本地所有綁架和綁架未遂案件 看是否有相似情況
We need to look at every local abduction Or attempted one in the past year, See if there's any overlap.
好消息是 現在才是被綁的第二個小時
Good news is that we're barely into the second hour.
很可能我們只剩22個小時的機會 把Aimee活著救出來 這就行動吧
Yeah,well,odds are we've only got 22 hours to find aimee alive, So let's do this.
今天早上10點 Aimee Lynch 最後被看見在Ashburn的的冬祭活動上
Aimee lynch of ashburn was last seen at the winter festival This morning at 10:00.
她身高4英尺8 金色頭髮 綠色眼睛
She's 4'8",has blond hair and green eyes.
頂著嚴寒的天氣和下雪的可能性 搜尋工作壓力非常大
With temperatures below freezing and a chance of snow, The pressure's on to find her.
任何人如果有Aimee的任何消息 請撥打熱線
Anyone with information about aimee Please contact the hotline.
不好意思 我想跟Jareau探員說幾句話
Uh,excuse me. I'd like to talk to agent jareau.
我有什麼能幫你的麼?
Can I help you?
帶走Aimee Lynch的人 也帶走了我兒子
Whoever took aimee lynch took my son,too.
Ashburn每年都有冬祭  活動中從沒有一起綁架未遂
Ashburn has a winter festival every year, And not a single attempt at kidnapping.
JJ 外面有個女人說 她的兒子被同一個人給拐走了
Hey,jj,there's a woman here who says her son Was abducted by the same offender.
- 她又喝酒了吧? - 是的 我很肯定 你為什麼會知道?
- Has she been drinking? - Yeah,I'm pretty sure. How'd you know that?
Sarah Hillridge 她8年前失去了兒子Charlie
Sarah hillridge. She lost her son charlie 8 years ago.
每次有跟她兒子年齡差不多的小朋友失蹤 她都會來這
She comes in every time a child around his age goes missing.
- 她認為她的兒子還在世? - 是的 我知道
- She thinks her son is still alive? - Yeah,I know.
我記得她 頭24個小時她都會待在這 是吧?
I remember her. She stays for the first 24 hours,right?
是的
Yeah.
現在只剩8小時了
There's only 8 hours left.
還要咖啡麼?
Any more coffee?
不了 不了 我很好 謝謝
Oh,no,no. I'm fine,thanks.
- Henry呢 他16個月了吧? - 17個月
- What's henry,is he 16 months? - Uh,17.
你女兒最近怎麼樣了?
Uh,how's your daughter?
- Jake把她帶走了 - 什麼?
- Uh,jake took her away. - What?
他再婚了 他覺得給Emily一個新開始 對她來說是最好的
Well,he got remarried,and,uh, Thought it was best for emily to get a fresh start.
我很遺憾
Sorry.
也不能怪他 你看看我這狀況
Well,I can't really blame him. I mean,look at me.
- Sarah 我真得... - 這小女孩Aimee 她8歲 跟Charlie一樣
- Sarah,I really need-- - This little girl aimee was 8, just like charlie.
他們相隔了8年被拐走
They were taken almost 8 years apart.
我一直在讀有關性吸引方面的資料
Now,I have been doing a lot of reading about sexual attraction
我知道 在前青春期可能性最大 並且男孩女孩都在其中
And know that prepubescence has the greatest range And also a really huge crossover gender-wise.
我很抱歉 你都知道了
I'm sorry you know all of that.
本可以一輩子都不需要知道這些事 直到有人把我兒子拐走了
I could have gone my whole life without knowing it, But then someone took my son.
沒事 我不會傷害你的 過來
It's ok. I'm not gonna hurt you. Come here.
過來 來這
Come on,come here.
你叫什麼名字?
What's your name?
在他們給你一個新名字之前 你一定要把你的名字告訴我
You gotta tell me your name before they give you a new one.
你在幹嗎? 你這是在幹嗎?
What are you doing? What do you think you're doing?
這不公平 讓她走!
It's not fair. Let her go!
別這麼跟我說話!
Don't talk to me like that!
以後不准這麼跟我說話!
You will never talk to me like that again!
行 知道了
Ok. Got it.
當時一個媽媽在找她女兒 Aimee的母親被分散了注意
Aimee's mom was distracted by a mother looking for her daughter,
她怪自己不該走神
And she's blaming herself for looking away.
等一下 Sarah... Sarah  Charlie被帶走的時候 她說過同樣的事
Wait. Sarah--sarah said the same thing when charlie was taken.
有個母親說兒子丟了 到處找
There was a mother searching for her lost son.
你覺得... 你覺得這是個巧合嗎?
Do you... Do you think it's a coincidence?
還是... 詭計?
Or what? A ruse?
一個女人在找她的兒子  這很具體啊 對吧
A woman looking for her lost son-- That's pretty specific,right?
再加上開闊的環境 沒有任何保安? 是的
Add to that a target-rich environment With no security? Yeah.
如果那女人是托 故意來分散大家注意 那誰把Aimee帶走了? 同夥?
Ok,so,if the woman was a distraction,who took aimee? A partner?
如果是同一撥人 他們都干了快十多了
Well,if it's the same people, They've been doing this for close to a decade.
我跟你說過
I told you.
* 媽媽會給你買只小羊羔的 *
* mama's gonna buy you a billy goat *
犯罪心理 第五季 第16集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode16 Mosley Lane
尼采寫過 "希望是最邪惡的魔鬼 它不斷延長著人們的痛苦"
Nietzsche wrote, "hope is the worst of evils, For it prolongs the torment of man."
- 這樣就結束了? - 沒有
- So that's it,then? - No,it isn't.
那為什麼你們要走了?
Well,why are you leaving?
州里的每個警察都在搜尋你的女兒
Every available cop in the state is out looking for your daughter.
她已經被帶走超過24個小時了
Who's been gone for more than 24 hours.
我想我們都知道那是什麼意思吧
I think we both know what that means.
從概率來看 是沒錯 但是每件案子 都有其特別的地方
Percentile-wise we do, But every case is based on its own merit.
那這次有什麼特別的?
Well,what merit is this case?
先生 帶走Aimee的人 冒著很大風險
Sir,aimee was taken at high risk by whoever took her.
意味著這是有組織的行為 有謹慎計劃 很可能犯人不止一個
It means it was organized, meticulously planned, And likely more than one person.
這就意味著 他們有意要留著她
This suggests that they intend on keeping her.
留著她? 為什麼? Frank這是咋了?
Keeping her? For what? Frank?
留著她就意味著她還活著 我覺得這是你們現在唯一需要關注的
Keeping her means that she's alive, And I think that's really All you need to focus on right now.
你們要走了麼?
Are you leaving?
女士 我們的側寫不會變的 而且無數警官和探員也都在找你的女兒
Ma'am,our profile remains, As do hundreds of officers and many agents looking for your daughter.
現在 如果有任何和Aimee有關的消息 我們就會回來的
Now,if there's any information Pertaining to aimee, then we'll be back.
Lynch先生 您要知道的是 沒有什麼可能阻止他們綁走您的女兒
Mr. Lynch,I think you should know That nothing could have stopped these people From taking your daughter.
換了是我就不會撒手的
Yeah. I would have never let go of her hand.
Frank 別這樣 Frank
Frank,please. Frank.
我們已經盡力了
We've done all we can.
但這並不能讓我離開時好受些
It doesn't make walking away any easier.
確實是這樣
No,it doesn't.
他們要叫你Alison
They want to call you alison.
但這不是我的名字
But that's not my name.
那你叫什麼?
What is it?
我不能告訴陌生人
I'm not supposed to talk to strangers.
我不是陌生人 我是你哥哥
I'm not a stranger. I'm your brother.
你為什麼帶我來這兒?
Why did you bring me here?
他們叫我David
They call me david.
我要媽媽
I want my mommy.
告訴我你叫什麼
Tell me your name.
Aimee
Aimee.
好的 Aimee
Ok,aimee.
我們都認為Aimee應該還活著 大家都沒有放棄
Look,we all think that aimee could be alive. No one's given up on her.
這就是為什麼上百志願者和警察 在鎮上地毯式搜索
That's why there's hundreds of volunteers and officers Combing every inch of the county.
但他們是在河埵b森林塈銕芶
But they're dragging the rivers and digging up the woods.
如果Aimee還活著 還和不明嫌犯在一起 這些方法就都沒什麼用
That's not gonna help us if aimee is still with the unsub, If she's still alive out there.
Charlie呢? 他還活著麼?
What about charlie? Is he still alive?
Sarah相信他還活著
Sarah believes it.
JJ 八年了 她都在說同樣的話
8 years she's been saying the same thing,jj.
你有沒有想過 為什麼你忽然就開始相信她了?
Have you thought about why you suddenly believe her?
你覺不覺得可能因為你做媽媽了?
Do you think it might be because you're a mother?
是...是因為這個女人告訴我 八年前就是相同的伎倆
It's--it's because another woman Just walked in here with the same exact ruse Used 8 years ago.
這是事實 不是麼?
I can't deny that. Can you?
我要說的不過是 如果不把這看成一起單獨的綁架案
All I'm saying is, if we go from a single abduction
而是一個持續10年的連環綁架 一切就都不一樣了
To multiple abductions over 10 years, That changes everything.
我們必須依靠沒有偏見的側寫 來推斷這到底是什麼性質
We all have to be convinced that's what it is, Based on an unbiased profile.
失蹤的孩子干擾了家長
Ok. Distraction of a lost child.
在幾乎沒有保安的公共場所 八齡童被綁架
8-year-old victims taken from public places With little to no security.
這不僅僅是相同伎倆 這是個性簽名
That's not just the same ruse. That's a signature.
- 我可不是個母親 - Charlie現在應該16了
- And I'm not a mother. - Charlie would be 16 now.
我們都知道 有偏好的犯人傾向在 被害人進入青春期前把他們殺掉
We all know that preferential offenders Typically dispose of their victims Before they reach puberty.
或許Charlie還有別的用處
Maybe he serves another purpose.
Aimee的媽媽說不明嫌犯很瘦小
Aimee's mom said the unsub was slight.
要讓一個十幾歲的孩子老實聽話可不容易
It wouldn't be easy to keep a teenager under her thumb.
但她從他八歲時就和他在一起了
Except that she's had him since he was 8 years old.
到了現在 他已經完全服從於她了
By now,he's completely submissive to her.
把Charlie留在身邊也解釋了 我們為什麼從來沒有找到他的屍體
Keeping him could explain Why charlie's body was never found.
- Garcia - 您說
- Garcia. - Sir.
全國範圍追查十年內的記錄
Go back 10 years nationwide.
從潛在目標較多地點的綁架開始
Start with abductions and target-rich environments.
排除其中找到屍體或者救回人質的
Rule out any with bodily recovery, dead or alive.
- 我去告訴Sarah - 好的
- I'm gonna let sarah know. - Ok.
現在我們要從全新的視角 看Aimee被綁架的現場
We need to check out aimee's abduction site With new eyes.
- 他們回來了 - 誰呀?
- They're home. - Who is?
照他們說的做 明白麼? 這樣不會吃苦頭
Do what they say. Ok? It'll make it easier.
David! 你在這兒幹嘛?
David! What are you doing here?
又在照相麼?
Taking pictures again?
快給我滾出去! 滾出去
Now get the hell out of here! Get out.
Well...
好像有人睡在金髮姑娘的床上咯
Looks like somebody's been sleeping In goldilocks' bed.
這下面是什麼呦? 看看
What have we got under here? Let's take a little look-see.
你好啊
Well,hello there.
我想回家
I just want to go home.
Alison 你現在就在家呀
You are home,alison.
Sarah?
- Jane 現場還交還給你 - 謝謝 Bill
- Back to you,jane. - Thanks,bill.
- Aimee Lynch最後被看到時 穿了一件大衣... - Sarah 我是Jennifer
- Aimee lynch was last seen wearing a winter coat... - Sarah,it's jennifer.
當時她和家人在參加Ashburn的冬祭嘉年華
She was with her family at the winter festival In ashburn.
警方正在調查這起案子 所以她的家人還沒有發佈正式聲明
The family has not put out a statement yet, As the authorities are handling the case.
如果您有關於Aimee的線索 請撥打我們的熱線
Anyone with information about aimee Please contact the hotline.
Sarah?
側寫我並不難是不是?
Not hard to profile,is it?
你覺得我瘋了麼?
You think I'm insane?
- 沒有 - 那你怎麼想的?
- No. - What do you think?
我跟你一個想法
I think the same thing you do.
你什麼意思?
What do you mean?
我覺得綁了Aimee的 就是綁了Charlie的人
I think the same people that took aimee Took charlie.
我有東西給你看
I want to show you something.
2000年以來 超過200個兒童的屍體沒有被找到
Since 2000,over 200 children's bodies have not been found.
這是全國範圍 那在弗州呢?
Nationwide. What about virginia?
一共有12起失蹤或假定死亡
Of the missing and presumed dead, there are 12.
Charlie在這個名單上呆了八年了 Aimee剛剛也上了這個名單
Uh,charlie's been on the list for 8 years, Aimee just joined it.
那麼 Aimee是在Ashburn被綁架的 Charlie是八年前在Leesburg被綁架的
So aimee was taken from ashburn, Charlie from leesburg,8 years ago,
都是在距離高速半英里以內的地方 其他那些呢?
Both within a half mile of the highway. What about the others?
Karla Hartway在1999年被綁架 當時她八歲 是在Garrisonville
Karla hartway was abducted in 1999, Age 8,from garrisonville.
Stephen Shepherd 2003被綁架  也是八歲 在Arlington  Danny Kenman...
Stephen shepherd,abducted 2003, also 8,from arlington. Danny kenman...
6月12日四點在商場被綁架
Abducted June 12 at 4:00 from the mall.
他家長離婚了 他還沒有被找到
Parents divorced. He's still missing.
這些花是什麼意思?
What do the flowers mean?
找到他們的時候都死了
They were all found dead.
其他的都還沒有找到
But all the rest are still missing.
比如Tracey Cain 九歲 從公園消失了 兩個家長當時都在場
Like tracey cain,9, She vanished from a park, both parents present.
還有Jake Wusman 9月29日從石溪公園被綁架
And then jake wusman, abducted September 29 From rock creek park.
當時他一大家子都在 他們在野餐
He was with his entire family. They were on a picnic.
- 還有 還有... - Sarah
- And then there's-- - Sarah.
如果你想幫我們 就幫我做一件事
If you're gonna help us, I need you to do something for me.
你儘管說
Anything.
別再酗酒了
Stop drinking.
可以可以 沒問題
I can do that. I can do that.
我們不應該帶Barbara回來麼?
Shouldn't we bring barbara back here?
不 她已經盡力了 讓我們再過一遍
No,she's given us all she can. Let's go through it.
好的 她當時差不多站在這兒對吧?
Ok. She was standing about here,right?
現場很擁擠 全家都在
It's crowded. Families all around.
你餓了麼? 走 買點吃的去
Are you hungry? Come on. Let's get something.
不明嫌犯在觀察 等待最佳目標
The unsubs are watching and waiting for the best target.
我要騎那匹帶斑點的
I want to ride the spotted one.
好撓哦
It' too scratchy.
- 然後她聽到了喊聲 - Lindsay!
- Then she hears it. - Lindsay!
Lindsay! Lindsay! 有人看見我女兒了麼?
Lindsay! Lindsay! Has anyone seen my daughter?
她轉回身來的時候 Aimee已經不見了
By the time she turns around, aimee's gone.
那個喊狼來了的媽媽這時就不見了
The mother who just cried wolf moves off.
她可以聽到Barbara哭喊著找Aimee 但是...
She can hear barbara crying out for aimee,but...
Aimee不能回答她 因為不明嫌犯把她的頭埋在了自己胸前
Aimee can't answer Because the unsub has her face buried in his chest.
路人看到 覺得不過是家長抱著自己哭泣的孩子
To passersby, it looked like any parent Carrying a crying child.
30秒之後 她就被關進了車...
30 seconds later, She's concealed in the vehicle...
然後他們就離開了
And they're gone.
這輛車再去接那個媽媽 她上車 任務完成
The same one rolls up on our mother, She gets in,it's done.
誰在開車?
Who's driving it?
這至少需要三個不明嫌犯
It took 3 unsubs to pull this off.
如果也是這些人綁了Charlie 那就是團伙犯罪
If the same people took charlie, We're looking for a group.
他們在八年內至少拐走了兩個小孩
Well,if they've taken 2 or more children Over an 8-year period,
肯定會有人覺察到的
somebody must have noticed something.
他們怎麼隱藏受害人?
How do they keep the victims hidden?
- 弄清這個咱們就能找到他們了 - 不明嫌犯?
- Once we figure that out, we'll find them. - The unsubs?
還有孩子們
And the children.
- 這些花真漂亮 - 謝謝
- Beautiful,aren't they? - Thank you.
每株都是我親手種的
I planted each and every one of them myself.
我把這些玫瑰花看做被遺忘的靈魂
I like to think of these roses As the souls of the forgotten.
就好像這個年輕人
Like... This poor young man here.
Hotch 這是Sarah Hillridge
Hotch,uh,this is sarah hillridge.
Charlie被拐走的時候我們見過面
Oh,we met when charlie was taken.
我們這樣的人你肯定見過不少 看起來都是一個樣子
I mean,you know, you saw a lot of us. I'm sure we all look the same.
謝謝你能來 坐吧
Thank you for coming in. Have a seat.
這代表從公共場所被拐的小孩
All right,these represent kids Taken from public places.
每個案發地都不同 但有一個共同點
Locations are never hit more than once, But there is similarity in each.
商場 玩具店 嘉年華 遊樂場 遊行
Different malls,toy stores, Carnivals,theme parks,parades.
一家人本該感到安全的地方
Places where families should feel safe.
安保也不是很嚴
And where there isn't much security.
10年12個孩子?
That's 12 children over 10 years?
我們應該到每一家去探訪
We should interview all the families.
有幾家我認識 我們有個互助小組
I know a few of them. We had a support group.
很多人已經離開了
I mean,most of them have moved on.
可你還在這兒
But you're here.
3年前我看到了Charlie
I saw charlie 3 years ago.
你沒跟我提過這事
You didn't tell me that.
連我丈夫都不相信我 更別說你了
Well,my husband didn't believe me. Why would you?
說說怎麼回事
Tell us what happened.
一開始有段時間我一直看到他
At first,I saw him all the time.
我以為我看見了 據我所知這很正常
I thought I did, and from what I understand, That's normal.
可你不能就這麼過下去
But you can't survive that way.
所以我和Jake決定搬走
So jake and I promised that we would move on.
可幾年後我又看見他了 這次不一樣
But a few years later,I saw him. I mean,it was different.
在我的印象堨L一直沒長大 可我看見的Charlie已經十幾歲了
I mean,in my mind he had never aged, But this was a teenage charlie crossing the street.
他很快就不見了 但我肯定看見他了
And as quick as he was there he was gone again, But I know I saw him.
Jake不相信我
Jake didn't believe me.
他就是那天離開我的
That was the day he left me.
看見Charlie的時候你做了什麼?
What did you do when you saw charlie?
我喊他來著
I called for him.
- Charlie! - 你怎麼知道那是他?
- Charlie! - How did you know it was him?
我不確定 所以我又喊了一次
Well,I didn't,not for sure, so I called for him again.
- Charlie! - 他聽見了嗎?
- Charlie! - Did he hear you?
- 他回頭了 - 你丈夫沒看到他?
- He looked back. - And your husband didn't see him?
Charlie
Charlie.
人很多 他不見了 我又把他弄丟了
It was crowded. He disappeared. I lost him all over again.
我們要找那些家長重新登記備案
We'll be asking those parents To sign up for all that pain again.
如果他們搬走了...
If they've moved on...
如果能找回孩子 他們會試試看的
They'd take the chance if it meant their kids were alive.
頭髮再亂一點 長到脖子
Just flare up that hair a little bit more, And it went farther down his neck.
眉毛沒有那麼濃
His--his eyebrows are not quite as full.
Stephen失蹤了7年了?
Stephen's been missing 7 years?
是二月份 他現在該有15歲了
In February. He'd be 15 now.
你最後見到他是在玩具櫃檯?
And you last saw him in the toy section?
那是Sarah Hillridge?
That sar hillridge?
- 你認識她嗎? - 我們原來是朋友
- Do you know her? - We were friends.
我們都在互助小組
We were in a support group together.
Stephen是在Charlie之後一年被拐的
Stephen was taken the year after charlie.
- 你知道她瘋瘋癲癲的嗎? - 別管她了
- You know she's crazy? - Leave her alone.
- 她就是瘋子 - 不 這我可不知道
- She is. - No,sir,I don't know that.
盼著兒子回家不說
Wishing for your boy to come home is one thing.
她都自暴自棄了
She threw her whole life away.
她丈夫是個好人 而她連她的乖女兒都不能...
Her husband's a good man, And she's got a daughter who she can't even--
- 她為什麼要毀掉這一切? - 希望能使人麻痹
- Why would she ruin that? - Hope can be paralyzing,sir.
我們認為帶走Aimee Lynch的人 做這事已經很長時間了
We believe that the people who took aimee lynch Have been doing this for a very long time.
昨天的那個小姑娘?
The little girl yesterday?
你兒子失蹤前有沒有特別的事發生?
In the moments before your son was taken, Did anything stand out?
比如說?
Like what?
能把你注意力從他身上引開的事?
Anything at all that drew your attention away from him?
有那麼一會兒 可我沒在意 有個女的
Just for a moment, But I never thought anything about it. That woman.
- 在找他的兒子 - 我幫了她的忙
- Looking for her son. - I helped her.
天吶 她還謝我來著
Oh,god. She even thanked me for helping.
世事難料
You couldn't have known.
她就在我面前 怎麼拐走Stephen?
She was right in front of me. How could she have taken stephen?
因為她不是單獨作案
Because she's not working alone.
他們用這把戲製造了多起綁架
They've used this ruse in a dozen local abductions.
叫我們來就因為這個?
Is that why we're here?
他對我們都是這麼做的?
They've done this to all of us?
你覺得Stephen有可能還活著嗎?
Do you think there's a chance stephen's still alive?
- 一共有多少人? - 你是第四個
- How many are there? - You're the fourth.
但是以前還有過其他人
But there have been others.
- 他們人呢? - 在更好的地方
- Where are they? - Someplace better.
他們要叫我們吃晚飯了
They're gonna get us for supper.
可我不餓
But I'm not hungry.
你最喜歡吃什麼? 冰激凌?
What's your favorite food? Ice cream?
就假裝是冰激凌 然後都吃光 好嗎?
Pretend it's ice cream And eat it all up. Ok?
我想媽咪
I want my mommy.
你有好幫手 他們最厲害了
You're in good hands. There's no one better than them.
我知道
I know.
我放開了她的手
I let go of her hand.
就那麼幾秒鐘 可我一直擔心的是她
It was only for a second, But she's always been the one that I worried about.
- 你不能自責 - Frank責怪我
- You can't blame yourself. - Frank does.
他說得對 我應該握住不放的
And he's right. I should have held on.
Aimee以前走丟過...
Aimee's wandered off before,and...
孩子不見了的時候 就有種感覺
There's this feeling when they're out of your sight.
除非再看見他們 否則無法呼吸
It takes your breath away until you see them again.
所以我覺得我喘不過氣來
And I think that's why I can't breathe.
11個家庭都指認了同一個女人 40到50歲 在呼喊她的孩子
11 families have confirmed the same woman, 40 to 50 years old, calling for children.
有時她還會帶著一個小孩
In some cases, she even had a child with her.
她利用小孩進行綁架?
She actually used the kids for the abductions?
她自己的還是拐來的孩子?
Were they her own or the ones kidnapped?
我們認為她沒有孩子
We don't believe she's a mother.
大多數有傾向的女性罪犯都沒有
Most predisposed female offenders are not.
但她們是最暴力的
But they are the most violent.
你說她有同夥?
Y-you said that she's working with someone?
可能是個順從的男性
It's likely a subservient male.
但這個女人把自己和同夥隔開
But the woman separates herself from her partners.
她挑選受害人 同夥去冒險
She chooses the victim while they do the riskiest part--
他們抓了孩子就跑
They grab the child and manage the getaway.
這是他的青少年版
This is what he looks like as a teenager.
他又瘦又高 頭髮顏色也變深了
um,he's tall and thin. His hair is,um, darker than it was.
這就是他 這是Charlie
But--but that's him. That's--that's charlie.
他們為什麼冒險讓他出來?
Why would they take the risk Of letting him out in the world?
他們把他囚禁了8年
They've had him under their control for 8 years.
他要麼已經開始依賴罪犯 要麼就是受到了威脅
He's either got stockholm or he's being threatened.
"再抓一個小孩來 我們就不殺你"
"get us another kid, And we won't kill you."
Sarah... 去歇一會兒 好嗎?
Sarah... Let's take a break,ok?
好的 謝謝
Ok. Ok. Thank you. Thank you.
好了 在北弗吉尼亞州生活和工作
All right. So living and working in northern virginia.
相當於與世隔絕
It's most likely in isolation.
有一屋子小孩 鄰里間很難說清
I mean,there's no way to explain a houseful of kids At the neighborhood block party.
管住這麼多小孩可不容易
Managing this many children isn't easy.
應該有不符計劃的事件發生
There have to be incidents where things didn't go as planned.
我們從國內長途電話和騷擾事件開始
We should start with domestic calls and disturbances.
特別注意那些被 社會福利機構拜訪過的家庭
Concentrate on families who were visited by social services.
我去告訴Garcia
I'll get garcia.
很可能這些不明疑犯之前都被問過話
It's likely these unsubs were questioned before.
一旦我們縮小Garcia列出來的名單範圍 我們就要重新拜訪他們了
Once we narrow down garcia's list, we should revisit them.
這一長段時間  他們對Charlie都做了什麼
What they've been doing to charlie this whole time,
哦 我曾經希望他就這麼走了  這樣就不用每天都受折磨了
Oh,there were times that I had hoped he was dead Just so he wouldn't suffer every day.
我們知道這些罪犯 很擅長拐騙和隱藏受害者
We know these offenders are skilled at abductions And hiding their victims.
一般情況下  我們直到真相大白才回過神來
Usually,we don't know that until after the fact.
而你把我們引向那些罪犯  這樣的情況很少見
What you've brought us, to them,is rare.
我知道 但結果不會皆大歡喜的
I know,but it's not gonna end well for all of us.
我認出他了 他就在那兒
I recognize him. He was there.
當我們排隊的時候
When we were in line.
他的年齡去騎小馬不合適 我本該明白的
He was too old for the ponies. I should have known that.
我們身後沒幾個人 他就在其中
He was a few people behind us.
- 你也看到他了 - 是啊 他看上去就像平常小孩一樣
- You saw him,too. - Yeah. He seemed like a normal kid.
- 他還活著? - 等下 這是你的兒子?
- He's still alive. - Wait,this is your son?
- Charlie - 你兒子帶走了我孩子?
- Charlie. - Your son took my baby?
- Lynch夫人... - 你兒子帶走了Aimee?
- Mrs. Lynch- - Your son took aimee?
- 親愛的 別這樣... - 他是 他是他們中的一員
- Honey,come on. - He's--he's one of them.
他帶走無辜的孩子們
He's taking innocent children.
Aimee只有8歲 她根本無力防範
Aimee is 8 years old. She can't defend herself.
他明明知道! 他就這樣看著她!
And he knew that! He watched her!
他跟其他罪犯一樣邪惡
He's as bad as the rest of them.
- 她說的對 - 不 不 不 Charlie別無選擇
- She's right. - No,no,no. Charlie didn't have a choice.
他已經是他們中的一員了  他要怎樣才能忘記這樣的經歷?
He's one of them now. How is he ever going to forgethat?
他只是試圖活命
He's just trying to survive.
好吧 天啊
Ok. My god.
求你 別離開
Please stay with me.
- 她會來看你的 - 求你了
- She'll check on you. - Please.
就一會兒
Just for a minute.
誰讓你進來的?
Who let you in here?
求你了 抓我吧 別傷害她
Please,take me. Don't hurt her.
求你 別走
Please don't leave me.
好了 過去十年有107個家庭 被社會福利機構拜訪過
Ok,there are 107 families Visited by social services in the last 10 years.
這樣一家一家來也太多了
That's too many to go door to door.
我們得縮小範圍
We're gonna have to narrow that down.
我們必須知道 為什麼他們 一直待在北弗吉尼亞州
We need to figure out why they're staying In northern virginia.
他們的工作可能是關鍵
Their work could be the key.
他們在那個地區可能 有個兒童福利院作掩護
They could have a child-care facility on the premises as a cover.
這很有可能是個單方收入家庭  夫妻中有一人必須待在家媟蚥U孩子
You know,it's most likely a single income family. Someone has to be home to stay with the kids.
好的 這些想法都有用
Ok,all this helps.
他們之前都被問過話  所以我們要明白他們可能在演戲
They've been questioned before, So we can expect a rehearsed response.
- 單子上有多少是單方收入家庭? - 23個
- How many on that list are single income? - 23.
有什麼問題麼?
What's the problem?
我們要逐個敲開23個家門  而他們每個人都可能傷害過孩子
We're gonna be knocking on the doors of 23 families And all of them have done something bad to a kid.
我們沒有搜查令 只有側寫
We don't have a warrant. Just our profile.
如果我們搞錯了 又離開了那個家
If we get it wrong and leave that house,
他們會銷毀一切證據 包括孩子們
They'll destroy any evidence they have, including the children.
JJ 去找件Aimee穿過的衣服
Jj,get an article of aimee's clothing.
作什麼用?
What for?
給狗聞
It's for the dogs.
- 別管了 - 不 我做不到
- Leave it alone. - No,I can't.
你做得到的
Yes,you can.
8年了?
8 years?
在我早上醒來的那一瞬間...
There's a moment In the morning, just as I wake up...
有過那麼半秒的平和
Where there's a split-second of peace.
之後 就又回到這種狀態
And then,it all comes back. All of it.
是啊 我到現在都沒合眼
Yeah. I haven't slept yet.
我希望你能在需要睡覺之前找到她
I hope you get her back before you need to.
如果你這些年來從不曾相信  你的兒子還活著
If you didn't believe for all those years That your son was still alive,
那麼現在我們誰也不會在這兒
None of us would be here now.
如果他死了 我會感應到的
I would have felt if he was gone.
- 我需要Aimee的一件衣物 - 為什麼?
- I need an item of aimee's clothing. - Why?
她 她再也沒戴上去過
She--she never put it back on.
謝謝
Thank you.
Jenkins先生 我們是FBI
Mr. Jenkins,we're with the fbi.
我們想問您些問題
We'd like to ask you a few questions.
我們一個個敲門  你應該是我們第...你覺得呢?
We're going door to door. You must be our-- what do you think?
第40 第50個? 我搞不清楚了
40th,50th door,I don't know.
您介意我們進來麼?
Do you mind if we come in?
Hayden先生 你有幾個孩子?
Mr. Hayden, how many children do you have?
5個... 還有個快生了
5... One on the way.
他們現在在哪?
And where are they now?
Hayden先生
Mr. Hayden.
什麼?
I'm sorry?
我說 您這兒很寬敞啊
I said,you've got a lot of land here.
- 還有一屋子的孩子們 - 是的
- And a houseful of kids. - Yes,I do.
怎麼那麼安靜 他們出去了?
It's awfully quiet. Are they out?
我妻子帶他們出去了
My wife took them out.
去冬祭活動?
At the winter festival?
冬祭?
Winter festival?
- 在Ashburn - 不
- In ashburn. - No.
呃 這倒是個不錯的想法
Uh,but that's a wonderful idea.
我會跟我妻子提的  或許對孩子們有好處
I'll mention that to my wife. Might be nice for the kids.
- 那邊有小馬騎呢 - 哦 好極了
- They have pony rides. - Oh,great.
那麼 那些孩子跟您妻子長得像嗎?
So,uh,do the kids take after your wife?
有些人是這麼說
Some say they do.
要我幫什麼忙麼?
How can I help you?
哦 我們其實挺希望您太太在這兒呢
Oh,we were actually hoping that your wife would be here.
您知道她什麼時候回來嗎?
Do you know when she'll be back?
她帶他們去考察旅行了
She's got the kids out on a field trip.
你要出聲 我就殺了你媽媽
If you make a sound, I'll kill your mommy.
懂了麼?
Do you understand me?
過來
Come over here.
把你的房間清出來 現在
Clean out your room. Now.
那我把她叫回來
Uh,I can get her back here.
請吧 如果您不介意的話
Please. If you don't mind.
我得到外面轉轉 不好意思
I need to step outside. Excuse me.
為什麼你不直接打個電話呢
Why don't you go on ahead and,uh, Make that phone call.
- Hotch? - 你們發現了什麼?
- Hotch? - What have you got?
我們在莫斯利路2150號  只有丈夫在 Roger Roycewood
We are at 2150 mosley lane. Only the husband is here. Roger roycewood.
- 妻子和孩子呢? - 恩 出去了
- Wife and kids? - Yeah. Out.
他符合側寫麼?
He matches the profile?
房子地段也符合 很偏
So does the property. It's isolated.
你在街上看不到這房子
You can't see it from the street.
門上有備用鎖
They have extra locks on the doors.
車道上有輛小型貨車 他們還有張照片  堶惆滬茖k孩很像Charlie
There's a minivan in the driveway And a photo of a boy who looks a lot like charlie.
他在盯著你麼?
Is he onto you?
- 絕對 - 我們馬上就到
- Without a doubt. - We're on our way.
- 搜查令? - 還有警犬
- Search warrant? - And dogs.
只要那些孩子 在那房子附近或 就在屋 我們就能找到他們
If the kids are anywhere near Or in the house,we'll find them.
嗯 還是語音信箱
Uh,voicemail again.
我想你們倆可以晚點再來
I suppose y'all could come back later.
我想 咱們都知道這是不可能的
I think we both know that's not gonna happen.
好 我們走 別出聲
Ok,let's go. Keep quiet.
Stephen在哪? 她把他弄走了
Where's stephen? She took him away.
是因為他不願意去那場嘉年華嗎?
Is that because he wouldn't go to the carnival?
我說過了 你會見到他的 進去
I said you'd see him. Get in there.
我想 你拿搜查令了吧
I guess you got your warrant.
還有地下探測雷達
And ground-penetrating radar.
我們會找到你埋他們的地點的
We will find where you buried them.
那會傷到那些薔薇嗎?
Will that hurt the roses?
雷達會傷到花嗎?
The radar?
警官
Officer.
大門口的安全監控攝像
Security camera on the front door.
- 什麼? - 這是個鉸鏈
- What? - It's a hinge.
我們去把警犬帶下來吧
Let's get the dogs down here.
把那個袋子給我
Give me that sack.
- 這是什麼地方? - 我不知道
- What is this place? - I don't know.
那是什麼?
What's that?
那是Aimee Lynch嗎?
Is that aimee lynch?
他們把她的頭髮給染了
They dyed her hair.
這堶惆S有Charlie
There's none of charlie.
這些照片很可能就是他拍的
He probably took these pictures.
做什麼用?
For what?
當證據
Proof.
他們的工作呢? 我們認為可能 跟他們的謀生方式有聯繫
What about their work? We thought it could be tied To what they do for a living.
就業記錄 稅金 都沒問題
Employment records, taxes,it's all legit.
Roger一直都是個電工
Roger's an electrician, has been since forever.
- 那麼妻子呢? - 看起來她似乎是待在家
- What about the wife? - Looks like she stays at home.
我正在用她婚前的名字 對這些記錄 做交叉比對 Anita Weld Roycewood
I'm crossing these same records with her maiden name, Anita weld roycewood.
我想該查不出什麼來的  而我極少猜錯 所以... 我錯了
I don't think I'm gonna find anything.And I'm rarely wrong,so-- I'm wrong.
她家族在Leesburg有一家殯儀館
Her family owns a funeral home in leesburg.
你們離那不到10分鐘的路程
You're less than 10 minutes from it.
哦 上帝 自她孩提時代起 那家殯儀館就屬於Weld家名下了
Oh,god. The funeral home's been in the weld family Since she was a little girl.
靈車 棺材 小貨車 要把孩子們藏起來 法子多了去了
Hearses,coffins,vans, a million ways to hide the children.
我們不能把十年的棺材都挖出來啊
We can't dig up 10 years of coffins.
你可能用不著 他們有個火葬場
You might not have to. They have a crematorium.
我們在這幹嗎? 這是幹嗎?
What are we doing here? What's happening?
把她放到那堶
Put her in there.
把她放到那堶!
Put her in there!
不 不... 不 不不不...
No,no... No,no,no,no... Oh,no,no,no...
- 讓她閉嘴 - 不!
- Shut her up. - No!
你聽到我說的了嗎?
Did you hear me?
哦 不要...
Oh,no...
來吧 到這來
Come on. Come on over here,now.
當媽媽的乖孩子 好吧? 沒事的
Just be mama's big girl,ok? It's all right.
不 不! 不!
No,no! No!
過來 來吧
Come here. Come on.
放開她!
Let her go!
得了吧 開玩笑吧...
come on, you gotta be kidding--
她再也不能傷害我們了
She can't hurt us anymore.
好的 謝謝
All right. Thanks.
他們找到孩子們了
They found the kids.
是時候逮捕Roger Roycewood了
Time to arrest roger roycewood.
誰有這個榮幸?
Who gets the honors?
- 他人在哪? - 衛生間
- Where is he? - In the bathroom.
- 您現在感覺如何? - 說實話 我很怕
- How are you doing? - Honestly,I'm terrified.
我等了8年了 要是他不認識我了...
I've waited 8 years. What if he doesn't know me?
你幹這行有多久了 Reid博士?
How long have you been doing this,dr. Reid?
5年7個月零19天
5 years,7 months,and 19 days.
按你的經驗 通常會出現什麼情況?
In your experience, what normally happens?
Charlie被綁走的時候是8歲  這意味著 他處在童年的中期
Charlie was 8 when he was taken, Which means developmentally, he was in middle childhood.
他有強烈的是非感 並且正在 逐漸理解 自己在這個世界的位置
He had a stronger sense of right and wrong And a growing understanding of his place in the world.
智力上 他有了說出自己的 想法和感受的能力
Mentally,he had the ability to talk about his thoughts and feelings,
同時會關心他人 多過專注於自我
While have less focus on himself and more concern for others.
所以 你認為他會沒事的?
So you think he's gonna be ok?
有像您這麼一位 付出這麼多的母親 是的
With a mother like you who did all this, I do.
我是個博士 我信仰事實和統計概率
I'm a doctor. I put my faith in facts And statistical probabilities,
但是今天 8位家長將得到個說法
But today, 8 parents are gonna have closure.
3個孩子就要跟著親人回家了
3 children are going home with their families,
都是因為您堅信您的兒子還活著
All because you believed your son was alive.
這在我的見識 已經幾乎是奇跡了
That's as close to a miracle as I've ever seen.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我們聽說他們已經在回來的路上了 但 不知道Stephen是否也在其中
We heard they're on their way back, But we don't know if stephen's with them.
- Jake - 多謝電話通知
- Jake. - Thanks for calling.
你...嗯...得謝她
You,uh,need to thank her.
你看起來這麼高興
You look so happy.
你找到他了 你做到了
You found him. You did it.
- Charlie? - 媽
- Charlie? - Mom.
Charlie
Charlie.
我認識Stephen
I knew stephen.
他跟我情同兄弟
He was like a brother to me.
他記得我們嗎?
Did he remember us?
你們不會懷疑過這點吧?
You didn't doubt that,did you?
念著你們 是我們活下來的唯一辦法
Remembering you was the only way we survived.
Stephen...多大的時候...死的?
How old was stephen when-- When he died?
他是為了保護那個小女孩而死的
He died protecting that little girl.
哦 上帝
Oh,god.
他昨天還活著?
He was alive yesterday?
不... 不...
No... No...
我一直努力想要說什麼才好 一句"謝謝"簡直太蒼白了
I have been trying to think of something to say, And thank you just doesn't even come close.
- 您不用謝我們 - 不 我要謝
- You don't have to thank us. - Yes,I do.
你知道 多久沒有人信過我了嗎?
Do you know how long it's been Since someone believed in me?
你們就這麼被黑暗的事情包圍著
You are just surrounded by darkness.
為什麼要做這樣的工作呢?
Why do you do it?
為了這樣的日子
Because of days like this.
艾米莉-狄金森(美國女詩人)曾寫道
Emily dickinson wrote,
"希望是長著羽翼的生靈  於靈魂中幽棲"
"hope is the thing with feathers, "that perches in the soul,
"唱著無言的旋律 永不停息"
"and sings the tune without words, And never stops at all."
犯罪心理 第五季 第16集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode16 Mosley Lane